Guide to the National Education Association-Commissions records, 1918-1982 NEA1002.RG
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- National Commission for the Defense of Democracy, 1922-1982; 1944-1968; Series 6; 38.5 Linear Feet
  - Agenda Books [file 1/2], October 1959; Series 6 (Box 1065, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Books [file 2/2], October 1959; Series 6 (Box 1065, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Books [file 1/2], February 1960; Series 6 (Box 1065, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Books [file 2/2], February 1960; Series 6 (Box 1065, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Books [file 1/3], June 1960; Series 6 (Box 1066, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Books [file 2/3], June 1960; Series 6 (Box 1066, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Books [file 3/3], June 1960; Series 6 (Box 1066, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Books [file 1/2], November 1960; Series 6 (Box 1066, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Books [file 2/2], November 1960; Series 6 (Box 1067, Folder 1)
  - Agenda Books [file 1/2], February 1961; Series 6 (Box 1067, Folder 2)
  - Agenda Books [file 2/2], February 1961; Series 6 (Box 1067, Folder 3)
  - Agenda Books [file 1/3], June 1961; Series 6 (Box 1067, Folder 4)
  - Agenda Books [file 2/3], June 1961; Series 6 (Box 1067, Folder 5)
  - Agenda Books [file 3/3], June 1961; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 1)
  - American Association of University Professors, 1955-1957; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 2)
  - American Civil Liberties Union, 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 3)
  - American Driver and Safety Education Accident Insurance Policy, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 4)
  - American Jewish Committee, 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 5)
  - The American Right Wing During 1966, January 1967; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 6)
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 7)
  - Archives-Listing of Files, 1961; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 8)
  - American Federation of Teachers (AFT), 1966-1968; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography of A.C. Lambert's Works, October 1949; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 10)
    Lambert, A. C.
  - Bibliography of Articles and Books Published, 1953-1968; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 11)
  - Board's Recommendations to States on Unemployment Insurance, November 1944; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 12)
  - Brochures-"3rd Annual National Organizations Laboratory", 1961; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 13)
  - Brochures-"5th Annual Laboratories for Community Leadership Training", February 1964; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 14)
  - Brochures-"14th Annual Summer Laboratory in Human Relations Training", 1966; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 15)
  - Brochures-"18th Annual Summer Laboratory in Human Relations Training", February 1964; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 16)
  - Brochures-"American Educational Research Association", 1944; Series 6 (Box 1068, Folder 17)
  - Brochures-"The American Way of Publishing", circa 1960; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 1)
  - Brochures-"As Others See Us", 1961; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 2)
  - Brochures-"Better Schools and Federal Aid", 1948; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 3)
  - Brochures-"Bill of Rights for Childhood and Youth", April 1942; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 4)
  - Brochures-"Center for the Story of Instruction", circa 1965; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 5)
  - Brochures-"Congress and the Home Folks", November 1959; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 6)
  - Brochures-"Danger!! They're After Our Schools", 1948; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 7)
  - Brochures-"Education is a Federal Responsibility", 1959; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 8)
  - Brochures-"An Experimental Laboratory in Community Leadership Training", 1960; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 9)
  - Brochures-"The Freedom to Read", 1953; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 10)
  - Brochures-"A Fresh Approach to Training for Community Action", January 1963; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 11)
  - Brochures-"Human Relations Training", March 1962; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 12)
  - Brochures-"Index of Congressional Record Reprint", 1943; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 13)
  - Brochures-"Is Your Local Association on the Right Track to gain Lay Support for Federal Aid to Education?", January 1949; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 14)
  - Brochures-"Keep them Free", circa 1952; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 15)
  - Brochures-"Laymen Speak out for Federal Support of Education", March 1960; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 16)
  - Brochures-"Man at the Top", January 1963; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 17)
  - Brochures-"NASA Educational Publications", March 1965; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 18)
  - Brochures-"NEA Library Subscription Plan", July 1950; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 19)
  - Brochures-"National Organizations Laboratory", circa 1960; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 20)
  - Brochures-"On-Air News Reports from NEA's Convention in Detroit", circa 1971; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 21)
  - Brochures-"Our Children Must Be Educated", circa 1945; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 22)
  - Brochures-"Protestant Church Leadership Laboratory", circa 1961; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 23)
  - Brochures-"Publications from Adult Education Service", circa 1965; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 24)
  - Brochures-"SAM-NTL Workshops in Leadership Development", circa 1968; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 25)
  - Brochures-"The Student's Right to Read", 1962; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 26)
  - Brochures-"Summer", 1963; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 27)
  - Brochures-"A Teacher Wants to Know", circa 1970; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 28)
  - Brochures-"Today's Ways", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 29)
  - Brochures-"In Today's World...Of Staggering Responsibility", October 1961; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 30)
  - Brochures-"TOP Level Management Only", circa 1961; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 31)
  - Brochures-"Training Laboratory for School Executives", 1961; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 32)
  - Brochures-"The Truth about Federal Aid to Education", circa 1940; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 33)
  - Brochures-"UN Publications, A Selective List", circa 1965; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 34)
  - Brochures-"What About Their Safety", circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 35)
  - Brochures-"Your Share in a Billion Dollars", June 1944; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 36)
  - Carr, William G., 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 37)
    Carr, William G.
  - Centennial-15th Year Report of Defense Commission, circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 38)
  - Centennial Birthday Party Committee Materials Prepared, 1957; Series 8 (Box 4923, Folder 5)
  - Centennial Credo, 1957; Series 8 (Box 4923, Folder 6)
  - Character Education, 1950-1962; Series 6 (Box 4049, Folder 1)
  - Community Conference Material, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 39)
  - Conference of Public Employee Organizations, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 40)
  - Conscription Correspondence, 1925-1954; Series 6 (Box 1069, Folder 41)
  - "Conscription News", 1946; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 1)
  - "Conscription News", 1947; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 2)
  - "Conscription News", 1949; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 3)
  - "Conscription News", 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 4)
  - Conscription and Universal Military Training [file 1/5], 1947-1971; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 5)
  - Conscription and Universal Military Training [file 2/5], 1947-1971; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 6)
  - Conscription and Universal Military Training [file 3/5], 1947-1971; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 7)
  - Conscription and Universal Military Training [file 4/5], 1947-1971; Series 6 (Box 1070, Folder 8)
  - Conscription and Universal Military Training [file 5/5], 1947-1971; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 1)
  - "Crackpot" Letters, 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 2)
    Contains 2 pictures.
  - Defense Bulletins (Nos. 101-107), April 1965-March 1968; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 3)
  - Defense Commission, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 4)
    Contains 1 name badge.
  - Defense Commission Handbook: Local, State, National, 1959; series 2 (Box 4312, Folder 11)
  - Defense Commission and PR & R Committee Investigations Publication Lists, Undated; series 6 (Box 4400, Folder 3)
  - Dennis, Elizabeth, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 5)
    Dennis, Elizabeth
  - Discipline, 1955-1956; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 6)
  - Discipline Material, 1955-1956; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 7)
  - Does the Teaching Profession Need a Stronger Defense Commission? A Report of Stewardship: An Account of Twelve Years of Service to the Members of the NEA by Its Defense Commission, June 1953; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 5)
  - Education-Labor Conference, 1942-1944; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 8)
  - Education A National Problem....the Need for Federal Aid, January 1942; series 6 (Box 4281, Folder 3)
  - Education for Tolerance Conference, 1944; Series 6 (Box 1071, Folder 9)
  - Establishment of Professional Rights and Responsibilities, 1941-1942; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 1)
  - Expanded Program (Memos and Ideas), 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 2)
  - Flora, A.C., 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 3)
    Flora, A. Cline
  - Gilles, Mathilda, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 4)
  - Ginger, Lyman, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 5)
    Ginger, Lyman Vernon
  - Gingerich, Inez, 1956-1961; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 6)
    Gingerich, Inez
  - Givens, Willard E., circa 1955; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 7)
    Givens, Willard E.
  - Gore, George W., 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 8)
    Gore, George W.
  - Hand, Harold C., 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 9)
    Hand, Harold C.
  - Horace Mann League, 1958; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 10)
  - Information Pamphlet, undated; series 6 (Box 4383, Folder 4)
  - Investigation Reports Abridgments: Chicago, IL; Pasadena, CA; Miami, FL; Houston, TX; Grand Prairie, TX; Kelso, WA; State Education Agency of Utah; Twin Falls, ID; Oglesby, IL; Mars Hill, NC, 1960-1962; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Arizona-Chandler-Clippings, 1948; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 11)
  - Investigations-Arizona-Chandler-Correspondence, 1948; Series 6 (Box 1072, Folder 12)
  - Investigations-Arizona-Chandler-Hearing, March 1948; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Arizona-Chandler-Reporter's Transcript of Proceedings, March 1947; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Clippings, 1950-1951; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Correspondence, 1950-1953; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Documents, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Draft, 1951; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Electioneering Ethics, February 1958; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 7)
    Included four microfilm reels, "Clippings from the Independent", "Clippings from Star News", "Miscellaneous Clippings" and "Miscellaneous Clippings-Star News, etc", which have been removed and placed in the Media Materials series.
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Report of Investigations, June 1951; Series 6 (Box 1073, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Senate Investigating Committee on Education (8th Report), 1951; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-California-Pasadena-Senate Investigating Committee on Education (10th Report), 1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami, January 1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Clippings, 1949-1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Correspondence, 1949-1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Dolley, Robert, 1948-1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 6)
    Dolley, Robert
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Draft and Page Proof, October 1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Miscellaneous Material, 1949-1952; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Summary of Findings in Technical High Investigation, 1951; Series 6 (Box 1074, Folder 9)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Transcripts-Conference between NEA and Administrative Committee of the Lindsey Hopkins Vocational High School, January 22, 1952; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Transcripts-Conference between NEA and Dade County Vocational Association, January 23, 1952; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Transcripts-Conference between NEA and Former Instructors of Lindsey Hopkins Vocational High School, January 21, 1952; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Transcripts-Conference between NEA and Dr. James T. Wilson and Robert D. Dolley, January 22, 1952; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Transcripts-Conference between NEA and Members of the School Board, January 23, 1952; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Vocational Program Statements Protesting Existing Conditions, 1949; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Florida-Miami-Wilson, James, 1949-1952; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 7)
    Wilson, James
  - Investigations-Idaho-Twin Falls, 1949-1950; Series 6 (Box 1075, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Elgin-Report, 1922; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Oglesby-Clippings, 1949-1951; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Oglesby-Documents, 1947-1951; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Oglesby-Draft, May 1951; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Oglesby-General Correspondence, 1949-1951; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Oglesby-"Some Considerations of the Detrimental Effects of Nepotism, Politics and Unionism upon Oglesby Publuic Schools", circa 1951; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Illinois-Oglesby-Testimony, 1951; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary, 1955-1958; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Case Notes, circa 1953; Series 6 (Box 1076, Folder 9)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Clippings, 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Comments, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Consultant Firms, 1953; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Draft and Gallery Proof, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Miscellaneous Documents, 1953-1955; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-News Releases, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Notes of Testimony, circa 1953; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-PAS Copyright Matter, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-PAS Education Consultants, 1955-1957; Series 6 (Box 1077, Folder 9)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Special Committee, 1955-1957; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Special Mailings, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Studies [file 1/2], 1947-1954; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 3)
    Contained "Public School System of Gary, Indiana", by the Public Administration Service, 1955.
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Studies [file 2/2], 1947-1954; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Indiana-Gary-Survey Report, School Buildings and Sites, March 1947; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Administrative Code, August 1959; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Committee, August 1955; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Clippings, 1954-1956; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Correspondence [file 1/2], 1949-1951; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 9)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Correspondence [file 2/2], 1949-1951; Series 6 (Box 1078, Folder 10)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Correspondence, 1955-1956; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Documents, 1949-1950; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Report Final Draft, 1955; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-A Report of a Study of the Organization and Administration of Business Affairs, September 1948; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Missouri-Kansas City-Revised, Estimated Operating Budgets, July 1955; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Montana-Polson, 1951; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Nebraska-McCook-Clippings, 1946-1947; Series 6 (Box 1079, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Nebraska-McCook-Correspondence, 1946-1957; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Nebraska-McCook-Documents, 1947; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Nebraska-McCook-Report of Investigation, March 1947; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-New Hampshire-Newport, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Annual Report to the Board of Education, 1952-1953; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Annual Report to the Board of Education, 1954-1955; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Clippings, 1955-1957; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Correspondence, 1955-1960; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Documents, 1954-1955; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 9)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Drafts, 1956; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 10)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Notes, 1955; Series 6 (Box 1080, Folder 11)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Survey of Organization and Administration, October 1953; Series 6 (Box 1081, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Hawthorne-Clippings, 1947-1957; Series 6 (Box 1081, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Hawthorne-Correspondence, 1957-1958; Series 6 (Box 1081, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Hawthorne-Documents [file 1/2], 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1081, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Hawthorne-Documents [file 2/2], 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1081, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Bridgewater-Investigation, December 1955; Series 6 (Box 1081, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-New Jersey-Hawthorne-Report, 1958; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-New Mexico-Taos, 1945-1947; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-New York-New York City-Clippings, 1943; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-New York-New York City-Correspondence, 1943-1959; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-New York-New York City-Report of a Survey of the New York City Board of Examiners, 1939; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-New York-New York City-Requests for Investigation, 1943; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-New York-New York City-Transcript, December 6, 1943; Series 6 (Box 1082, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-North Carolina-Mars Hill-Clippings, 1951; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-North Carolina-Mars Hill-Correspondence, 1949-1951; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-North Carolina-Mars Hill-Documents and Drafts, circa 1952; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-North Carolina-Mars Hill-Preliminary Notes, September 1950; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-North Carolina-Mars Hill-Report, 1949-1950; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Ohio-North College Hill-Clippings, 1947; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Ohio-North College Hill-Correspondence, 1946-1948; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Ohio-North College Hill-Documents, 1941-1947; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Ohio-North College Hill-Final Draft, 1947; Series 6 (Box 1083, Folder 9)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Clippings [file 1/2], 1953-1954; Series 6 (Box 1084, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Clippings [file 2/2], 1953-1954; Series 6 (Box 1084, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Correspondence, 1948-1954; Series 6 (Box 1084, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Correspondence (Favorable), 1954; Series 6 (Box 1084, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Correspondence (Opposition), 1953-1954; Series 6 (Box 1084, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Directory, 1953; Series 6 (Box 1084, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Documents, 1952-1957; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Draft (Second), November 1954; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Final Proof, December 1954; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-General Research Company [file 1/2], 1953; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-General Research Company [file 2/2], 1953; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Materials Related to Survey Questionnaire, 1954-1957; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Minute Women Series, 1953-1954; Series 6 (Box 1085, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Report, November 1954; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 1)
  - Investigations-Texas-Houston-Survey Data Sheets, circa 1954; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 2)
  - Investigations-Utah-State Educational Association of Utah, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 3)
  - Investigations-Utah-State Educational Association of Utah-Correspondence, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 4)
  - Investigations-Utah-State Educational Association of Utah-Documents, 1947-1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 5)
  - Investigations-Utah-State Educational Association of Utah-Report Drafts, circa 1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 6)
  - Investigations-Washington-Kelso-Correspondence, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 7)
  - Investigations-Washington-Kelso-Draft and Clippings, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 8)
  - Investigations-Washington-Kelso-Minutes of Investigating Team, 1950; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 9)
  - Kawanishi, Susumu, 1956; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 10)
    Kawanishi, Susumu
  - Lay Conferences, 1943-1945; Series 6 (Box 1086, Folder 11)
  - Lay Conferences-General, 1944-1945; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 1)
  - Lay Conference on Postwar Problems and Education, 1945; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 2)
  - "Legal Aspects of the Board of Education" (Thesis by F. Juchhoff), 1937; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 3)
  - Legislative Commission Photos, 1967; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 4)
    Contains 7 photos and 31 negatives.
  - Let's Put First Things First to Make America Strong, 1948; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 7)
  - Maehling, Hilda, 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 5)
    Maehling, Hilda
  - Management Survey, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 6)
  - McSwain, Elderidge T., 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 7)
  - Merit Rating, 1956-1957; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 8)
  - Milestones in the Professional Standards Movement, 1956-1962; series 6 (Box 4312, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous Papers, 1958-1961; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 9)
  - More-than Tolerance: Suggestions to Teachers on Inter-Group Education, May 1946; series 6 (Box 4292, Folder 8)
  - NEA Centennial Celebration [1 of 2], 1957; Series 8 (Box 4923, Folder 3)
  - NEA Centennial Celebration [2 of 2], 1957; Series 8 (Box 4923, Folder 4)
  - NEA Centennial Birthday Party, April 4, 1957; Series 8 (Box 4923, Folder 7)
  - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 10)
  - NEA of the U.S.: Some Basic Facts about America's Largest Professional Association, circa 1955; series 6 (Box 4292, Box 9)
  - National Organization on Legal Problems of Education, 1957; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 11)
  - Nebraska Conference (Pupil Behavior), 1956-1958; Series 6 (Box 1087, Folder 12)
  - Open Meeting (Portland, OR), 1956; Series 6 (Box 1088, Folder 1)